A Guide to the Deneufville Family Papers, 1785-ca. 1850
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Deneufville Family Papers, 1785-ca. 1850.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 41.2
18 items.
Deneufville Family.; Jean Augustine Deneufville, 1763-1838.; Peter Robert Deneufville, d. 1809.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1941.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1120 and in transcription TR/65.
Biographical/Historical Information
The brothers Jean Augustine (1763-1838) and Peter Robert Deneufville (d. 1809), came to Hanover County and Williamsburg, Va., from France about 1780 and became merchants.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, primarily 1785-1815, of brothers Jean Augustine (1763-1838) and Peter Robert Deneufville (d. 1809). Included are letters from merchants, customers, and friends; bonds; receipts; a copy of Peter Robert Deneufville's will in which he stipulates that his slave Betty and her children be freed and given some articles of clothing and bedding and fifty pounds Virginia currency; a letter between two of Augustine's granddaughters; a land grant from the governor of Georgia, Edward Telfair, to Daniel McLane; and indentures between various Deneufville relatives. Names prominent in the papers include Robert Anderson, Andrew Buchanan, James Lee, John Saunders, John Taliaferro, Edward Teagle, and Dr. Wiscart.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Deneufville family.
Persons:
Anderson, Robert, 1781-1859.; Buchanan, Andrew, fl. 1792.; Deneufville, Peter Robert, d. 1809.; Deneufville, Jean Augustine, 1763-1838.; Lee, James, fl. 1836.; McLane, Daniel.; Saunders, John, fl. 1805.; Taliaferro, John.; Teagle, Edward.; Wiscart, Dr.
Subjects:
African Americans--Virginia--New Kent County.; Merchants--Virginia--Williamsburg.; Slaves--Virginia--New Kent County.
Geographical Names:
Virginia--Genealogy.
Genre and Form Terms:
Deeds--Virginia--Williamsburg--1815.; Indentures--Virginia--1806.; Land grants--Georgia- -1790.; Wills--Virginia--James City County--1809.; Wills--Virginia--New Kent County-- 1809.
Contents List
- Fourra to Neuville, 8 February 1785. (Folder 1)
- Gourdin to Augt. Deneufville, 21 September 1785. (Folder 1)
- LeCointe Freres to Augt. Deneufville, 12 June 1787. (Folder 1)
- Letter to Andrew Buchanan, 17 April 1792. (Folder 1)
- Herbert Claiberne to Doctor Wiscart, 28 November 1792. (Folder 1)
- C. L. Levent to Peter Robert Deneufville, 27 March 1798. (Folder 1)
- Louis Pagaud to Peter Robert Deneufville, 1 August 1798. (Folder 1)
- John Saunders to Peter Robert Deneufville, 24 October 1805. (Folder 2)
- Indenture, Henry Gibbs and Reuben Howes to Peter Robert Deneufville, 14 April 1806. (Folder 2)
- Receipt, J. Semple to Peter Robert Deneufville, 26 June 1807. (Folder 2)
- Richard Maupin receipt to Peter Robert Deneufville, 26 February 1808. (Folder 2)
- Last Will and Testament of Peter Robert Deneufville, which directs his executors to free his slave Betty and her children and to provide them with certain goods, and fifty pounds Virginia currency, 9 October 1809. (Folder 2)
- Exceptions of J.A.D. to Statement P., [8 August 1812] (Folder 2)
- Deed. Robert Anderson, Helen Maxwell, to Edward Teagle. For part of Block 17 Lot 57 [John Crump House], 23 May 1815. (Folder 2)
- Indenture, William H. A. Teagle and James Lee, 28 September 1836. (Folder 2)
- [Louisa Deneufville] to [Mary] Marion [Deneufville], 14 August 185[0] (Folder 2)
- Letter with seal attached & plat. Grant to Daniel W. Lane for 1000 acres, from Georgia's Secretary's office, 1 September 1790. (Folder 3)